# Mike Dougherty

# Code Whisperer and Remodeler

## **Contact Info**

• Phone: 858.232.3635

• Email: miked@threedev.io

• LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikedougherty/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikedougherty/</a>

# Summary

I am currently a Lead Code Whisperer at Corgibytes and have almost 30 years of experience in software engineering and consulting and have led numerous large-scale and multi-year projects in a wide variety of technology stacks and cloud-based infrastructure. He enjoys working collaboratively with teams to solve complex problems, whether they are related to stabilizing and refactoring legacy code, re-architecting application components, or finding better ways to test, build and deploy with modern tooling.

# Experience

## **Lead Code Whisperer**

Corgibytes, Richmond, VA May 2019 - Present

- As a member of the team working to help Capital One Financial (COF) modernize their Java and Scala microservices to reduce code complexity and duplication and migrate to new CI/CD pipelines and code analysis tools and requirements.
- As a member of the team working on Shelterluv's Drupal 7 based application, helping modernize, detangle and apply the Strangler Pattern to prepare them for rapid development and deployment as they target a Macroservice Architecture for the future of the application.

#### Senior Consultant / Architect

Three Dev, San Diego, CA 2003 - Present

Architect, develop and maintain custom software solutions for various clients in Java, Objective-C and other languages..

- Developed assorted Java EE (JSF, EJB, JPA) applications including WaveReg.com and thelifeapp.us.
- Developed iOS and Android applications iForget, Horizon, Rock Mobile.

858.232.3635 - miked@threedev.io - http://threedev.io

• Developed Java EE Mogiv SMS and online donation platform - mogiv.com.

### **Software Developer**

Itdesign, GmBH, Tübingen, Germany

2014 - 2017

- Develop, debug and support GWT/GXT application itd: Assignment Editor and itd: Allocation Editor.
- Scrum Product Owner for itd: Assignment Editor, itd: Allocation Editor and other PPM products.
- Project manager for U.S. customers and projects.

## Java Architect / Engineer

iBASEt, Inc. San Diego, CA

2004 - 2006

• Architecture, design, and development of FORCEnet Implementation Tool Suite (FITS) and Ship Maintenance Process Java EE applications.

#### Senior Java Engineer

XIFIN, Inc. San Diego, CA

2002 - 2004

- Designed and Implemented MVC (Model View Controller) framework for use in Swing applications.
- Rewrite of Order Entry as Web application using Struts MVC framework.
- Architecture and design of Laboratory Order and Reporting (LOR).

#### **Lead Java Engineer**

Cogenisys, Inc., San Diego, CA

2001 - 2002

- Develop runnable Java EE application by applying industry design patterns to UML model.
- Develop XSL templates for generating runnable Java EE application from UML model.

#### **Lead Java Engineer**

Aradiant Corporation, San Diego, CA

2001 - 2001

- Analyzed current dispatch program, operator agent uses and needs, to gather requirements.
- Developed proof of concept and prototype with J2EE and Swing technologies.

## **Lead Java Engineer**

Teradata CRM, San Diego, CA 2000 - 2001

- Designed and developed adapter factory to turn user expressions into Java byte code.
- Designed and developed framework for rules engine processing.

#### **Java Engineer**

MediaDNA Inc., San Diego, CA 1999 - 2000

- Assisted in the design and development of the DRM system
- Designed and developed customer service and administration application for the DRM system

#### **Java Engineer**

MessageMedia Inc. (formerly First Virtual Holdings Inc.), San Diego, CA 1995 - 1999

- Design, develop and maintain web administration console for the IMC (Interactive Messaging Center)
- Administration, research and support for the VirtualPIN transaction platform

## Skills

Languages/Markup: Java EE, PHP, Solidity, Javascript/Typescript, Objective-C, XML, XSL
Data/ETL: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, NoSQL (i.e. MongoDB, Datastore/Firestore, etc)
Infrastructure/Cloud/DevOps: GCP, AWS, GitHub Actions, BitBucket Pipelines, Jenkins, Linux, macOS, Unix

Frameworks: JPA/Hibernate, JSF/JSP, Spring, Struts, Laravel, Foundry, Android, iOS

**Web Services**: REST, gRPC, SAML, SOAP, XMLRPC, OAuth **SDLC**: Agile, SCRUM, Kanban, TDD, BDD, Jira, Trello

# Education

# **Business Administration and Management**

University of Redlands, San Diego, CA

# Level 1 Information Assurance Training & Level 3 Unix System Administrator

SAIC Inc., San Diego, CA

## **B1 Language Certification in German**

Bundesamt für Migration und Flüchtlinge, Tübingen, Germany